RYAN P. MALONEY

Current Address: 65 Hobart Street Brighton, MA 02135 ♦ rypmaloney@gmail.com ♦ (508) 641-6024

SUMMARY

Highly motivated English literature major with an interest in public and scholarly communications. Strong interpersonal skills and strong communication skills. Professional experience in the management of an institutional repository, supervising digitization projects, and supporting publishing staff.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS AMHERST, Commonwealth Honors College Amherst, MA

June 2016

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature, Cum Laude

Completed Honors Thesis in postmodern literature and the academic fiction of John Barth

UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS SUMMER SESSION, Oxford, England

August 2014

- Participated in six week intensive summer session at Trinity College, Oxford.
- Winner of 2014 Ernest Hofer Prize for Best Paper In English Literature

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY, New York, NY

September 2012 - April 2013

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ACADEMIC TUTOR, APT Tutoring & Test Prep

April 2017 - Present

- Tutor students from middle school through high school in English and History
- · Specialize in essay writing for form, content, and accuracy

SUPPORT STAFF MEMBER, UMass Scholarly Communications

May 2016 - August 2016

- Trained student employees in archive maintenance
- Worked on grant proposal process and implementation of the Outernet Project, providing open access educational materials to internet poor communities
- Oversaw the migration of UMass Center for International Education to the repository
- Assisted faculty in fair use and open access publication
- Supported Scholarly Communications staff in the expansion of the open access movement on campus

STUDENT ASSISTANT, UMass Office of Scholarly Communications

April 2015 - May 2016

- Assisted in the management of an institutional repository
- · Digitized and archived hundreds publications
- Assessed copyright status of faculty publications

ATHLETIC TUTOR

February 2015 – July 2015

- Assisted student athletes with Communications and English courses
- Worked specifically on essay writing, editing, and outlining

COMMUNITY SERVICE

AMERICA READS AND AMERICA COUNTS

Tutor

January 2013 - April 2013

- Tutor 7th grade students in natural and physical sciences
- Grade daily homework assignments
- Work one-on-one, teaching challenging concepts

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe InDesign, Silverstripe, Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram. Able to quickly learn new software and design skills.